tut.com 2019-12-09

# TUT - The Universe Talks - Mike Dooley

Last Updated and Effective as of: October 9, 2019

Tut.com is operated by TUT Enterprises, Inc., (hereinafter, “we”, “our” or “us”). The privacy policy below discloses our practices regarding information collection and usage solely for the website located at www.tut.com. 

### INFORMATION COLLECTION & USAGE:

The personal information that you submit to us is completely voluntary. We do not collect personal information unless you submit that information to us through your usage of our website. We do not and will never sell your email address or other personal information. Data submitted to us is only available to employees and contractors managing this information for purposes of sending out our daily _Notes from the Universe_ emails and sharing information about events, monthly happenings, and special offers. Any information you provide will be held with the utmost care and will not be used in ways that you have not consented to. By interacting with tut.com, you consent to the transfer and processing of all data, including your personal information, at facilities located in the United States. If you have any questions, please feel free to e-mail us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#c0a1a4b6a5aeb4b5b2a580b4b5b4eea3afad).

We collect information about you and your visits to our site and services in order to:

  * Provide you with the services that you seek from our website;
  * Improve our website and services;
  * Ensure the security of our website;
  * Better market relevant content;, using anonymous or pseudonymized personal data;
  * And market to you specifically, such as through email and web retargeting.

### TYPES OF DATA WE COLLECT

Categories of personal information we may collect include identity data such as name or other similar identifiers and contact data such as mailing address, email address, and telephone number. We may also collect additional types of information that, along with identity data and contact data, may be considered and specifically named “personal data” in certain jurisdictions, including the European Union. This information includes financial data such as credit card, debit card, or other payment card details submitted by you through the purchase of our services. Our site also collects technical data such as internet protocol (IP) address, location data, your login data, including username and password, and device and browser information provided while using out website, and usage data that informs us of how you use our website and the advertising we serve to you through your usage of tut.com.

Data on our website is collected through a variety of methods including direct interactions such as signing up for _Notes from the Universe_ , creating an account, registering for events, purchasing products, providing feedback, and contacting us directly through email and the “contact us” option on our website.

By using [tut.com](https://www.tut.com/), you consent to the collection of data using automated technologies or interactions including cookies and tracking pixels. When you visit our website, our system automatically collects information about your visit, such as your browser type, your IP address, and the referring website. This collection may be done in conjunction with our vendors. We may receive from them general demographic or usage data of our site visitors. We do not use automatically collected information to identify you personally without collecting additional consent. Such information is typically collected using web cookies, web pixels (also known as beacons), embedded hyperlinks, and similar tools. Popular browsers can generally be set to disable or delete individual cookies. See below for the types of cookies we use and their respective purposes.

Required Cookies: enable the navigation and basic functionality of the website, e.g., access to protected areas of the website.

Functional Cookies: allow us to analyze your website usage and your selections on the website (e.g. your login name or region), so we can save these settings and offer you a more personalized experience.

We use cookies to provide the best possible experience on our site and show you personalized content. By clicking “accept” on the cookies notification banner that appears when you first access our site, you consent to the use of our cookies by default. You may update your cookie setting at any time using your browser settings. To change your browser’s settings, follow the appropriate link based on the browser you use: [Android](https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/61416?co=GENIE.Platform%3DAndroid&hl=en), [Chrome](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?co=GENIE.Platform%3DDesktop&hl=en), [Firefox](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences), [Safari](https://support.apple.com/guide/safari/manage-cookies-and-website-data-sfri11471/mac), [Safari for iOS](https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201265), and [Internet Explorer](https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies).

In addition to cookies, our website uses [Google Analytics](https://analytics.google.com/), a web analysis service of Google, Inc. (“Google”). Learn more from their Terms of Service and Privacy Policy. To opt-out, download the browser plugin “Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on” here.

Our website uses Google AdWords Conversion Tracking cookie to measure and optimize the performance and user experience related to our ads in Google Search or selected Google Display Network sites. Learn more about Google’s privacy policy [here](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en). To opt-out, visit [Google’s Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads).

### CREDIT CARD SECURITY:

All credit card purchases are placed over our secure server connection. To ensure you are on our secure server make sure you see a padlock on the bottom of your browser window. Make sure you do not enter any credit card information unless you see this padlock. It should be present whenever you are in our shopping cart.

### THIRD PARTY LINKS AND SOCIAL NETWORKING SERVICES:

This site contains links to other sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such other sites. We currently use Constant Contact, Ontraport, and Kajabi, third-party services, for managing our emails and online content. Please refer to their privacy policies for any questions about their practices. Links in our emails to third parties may earn referral fees to help defray the cost of the free Notes from the Universe service.

We may engage the use of additional third-party vendors, including social media websites like Facebook, Instagram, and Twitter, to use your information in connection with their own information to deliver targeted advertising to you when you visit our website or other websites. Cookies, described above, may be used in this process.

### CHOICE/OPT-OUT:

This site offers users the option to instantly opt-out/unsubscribe from mailings and to cease receiving all future communications. You may also email us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#a0c1c4d6c5ced4d5d2c5e0d4d5d48ec3cfcd) with such requests or when assistance is needed.

Under certain circumstances, you have rights under local data protection laws in relation to your personal data. You have the right to request access to your personal data and request corrections of your personal data at any time. You also have the right to request the deletion of the personal data we hold for you. If you would like to request access to your personal data or request corrections, please contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#86e7e2f0e3e8f2f3f4e3c6f2f3f2a8e5e9eb).

You are allowed and able to withdraw consent to collect and process your personal data at any time by emailing us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#51303527343f25242334112524257f323e3c). However, this request will not affect the lawfulness of any data processing carried out before you withdrew your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.

We may need to request specific information from you in order to confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data. This is a security measure that will ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who does not have the right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

### DATA RELATING TO CHILDREN

Our website and emails are designed for those 18 years of age and older. We do not knowingly collect information from anyone under the age of 13 (or such other age as may be restricted under local law). If we are made aware that we have received such information, or any information in violation of our policy, we will use reasonable efforts to locate and remove that information from our records.

### PRIVACY POLICY CHANGES:

We reserve the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions of this privacy policy at any time without prior notice. Upon a material change in policy, we will post changes here on our website or email you. Your continued use of the website and/or its services will constitute your consent to the updated policy. We encourage you to periodically review our privacy policy for the latest information on our privacy practices. If you do not agree with the terms of this policy, please don’t use the website.

### CONTACT US:

If you have any questions regarding this privacy policy, you may email us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#5a3b3e2c3f342e2f283f1a2e2f2e74393537) or via snail mail at 6465 Piazza Grande Ave, Suite 213, Orlando, FL 32835.
